You know I would not have called unless it was very, very important,
진짜 중요한 일 아니면
전화 안 했을 거 알잖아요
정말이에요
I promise.
그냥 인정해요
워커 양
Just face it, Miss Walker, you miss me already.
벌써 내가
그리운 거예요
The agency and the D.P.D. and yours truly
기관과 DPD와
당신의 업무는
are doing just fine without you, thank you.
Really?
당신 없이도
잘 진행되고 있어요
그래요?
Then what is so important that you had to call me on my vacation?
그럼 뭐가
그렇게 중요해서
휴가 중인 사람한테
전화를 걸어요?
I can't remember the name of that salad that I like from the cafeteria.
내가 마음에 들어했던
구내 식당의 샐러드 이름이
생각이 안 나요
Oh, well, that is serious.
저런, 그거
심각하군요
Okay, there is also something else I wanted to ask you.
알았어요
물어보고 싶은 게
하나 더 있었어요
I think it's amazing that you're going back
이스탄불에서 열리는
국제 재즈 축제에 가는 건
to the International Jazz Festival in Istanbul,
정말 멋진 일 같지만
but how exactly does a blind man navigate
어떻게 시각 장애인이
외국 도시에서 열리는
a huge music festival in a foreign city?
대형 음악 축제를
찾아갈 수 있죠?
I know Istanbul better than some Turks,
난 몇몇 터키인들보다
이스탄불을 더 잘 알아요
and for what I don't know I can always make a friend.
모르는 점에 있어서는
친구를 사귀면 돼요
Excuse me, sir,
실례합니다
can't you see that won't fit?
크기가 맞지 않는 게
안 보이세요?
No, actually, I can't see.
네, 정말로...
안 보여요
Oh. I'm sorry.
죄송해요
It makes it harder to win at darts, that's for sure.
확실히 다트 게임
이기긴 어렵죠
And to find a good place for your bag on a crowded plane.
혼잡한 비행기 안에서
가방 넣을 공간을
찾는 것도 그렇고요
Well, it's my job to take care of your bag, so don't worry about that.
가방은 제가
챙겨 드릴게요
걱정 안 하셔도 돼요
Thank you.
고마워요
So if you want to maybe talk about darts later
혹시 나중에
다트나 당신에게 적당한
체스 같은 이야기를
or a more suitable game like chess,
하고 싶으시면...
I could call out all the moves.
제가 상대가
되어 드릴 수 있어요
I'm actually killer at Battleship.
사실 저는
배틀쉽을 잘합니다
Done.
좋아요
Excuse me for just one minute.
잠시만요
잠깐만 실례하죠
Green goddess salad, no peanuts.
그린 가드니스 샐러드예요
땅콩은 빼고요
Made a friend already, huh? Hanging up now, Walker.
- 벌써 친구 사귄 거예요?
- 이제 끊습니다, 워커
전화 끊을 때 안녕이라고
말하는 법 좀 배워요
You know, you should learn to say good-bye when a phone conversation ends.
보통 사람들은
그런다고요
It's what normal people do.
What a perfect reason not to.
그럼 더더욱
할 수 없죠
Sorry about that.
실례했어요
이스탄불
= 터키 =
ISTANBUL TURKEY
오기!
Auggie.
Kasim.
카심!
Hey, Auggie.
이쪽이야!
그래, 잘 지냈어?
Hey! How are you?
Fine, dude.
괜찮게 지냈지, 친구
I didn't think you were coming this year.
Oh, and miss Jehan Barbur? No way.
올해는 오지
않을 줄 알았는데
제이헌 바부의
공연을 놓친다고?
그럴 순 없지
You have three parabolic microphones set up?
파라볼라 마이크
세 개 준비했어?
Four. I want to really try
and capture the ambient experience as possible,
네 개야, 공연뿐만 아니라
주변 환경의 소리를
가능한 한 정확히
잡아내고 싶어
not just the show.
And I'd love to plug my reel-to-reel
괜찮다면
내 오픈식 녹음기를
directly into the sound board if that's okay.
사운드 보드에
직접 연결하고 싶어
You also love me for this.
Oh, yeah.
이것도 맘에 들 거야
물론이지
Come with me, old friend.
가자고, 친구
Okay, I got it. I got it.
그래, 괜찮아
알아서 할게
♬ Kucuk Kadin ♬
Jehan Barbur
HOTEL SAPPHIRE ISTANBUL, TURKEY
사파이어 호텔
= 터키, 이스탄불 =
I still can't believe that you missed this today.
당신이 오늘 공연을 놓치다니
너무 아쉽군요
I can't believe you didn't come back sooner.
난 당신이 더 일찍 돌아오지
않아서 아쉬운데요
Well, while I appreciate that,
그건 인정하지만
you really did miss something special.
당신은 정말 특별한 걸
놓친 거예요
Listen to this.
들어봐요
이건 그냥
노래가 아니에요
That isn't just a song.
Those musicians are speaking to each other
이 뮤지션들은 서로
대화를 주고받죠
about the struggle to stay hopeful after loss,
희망을 잃지 않으려는
노력을 이야기하고
about believing that something better is always possible.
더 나은 미래에 대한
믿음을 노래하죠
- Yeah? - Mmm.
그래요?
Sounds like guitar to me.
You're lucky you're cute.
나한텐 그냥
기타 소리 같은데요
귀여우니까 봐주죠
You don't know that.
그걸 어떻게 알아요?
Oh, yes, I do.
난 알아요
Give me just a minute to finish up this mix.
믹스 끝낼 시간
잠깐만 더 줘요
See, I don't get that.
아직 모르겠는데
당신 음악 평론가예요?
Are you a music journalist or a sound engineer?
아니면 음향 기사예요?
Well, the first for money.
The second for love.
첫 번째 건
돈을 위한 거고
두 번째는
좋아서 하는 거죠
Well, actually both for love,
실은 둘 다 좋아서
하는 거지만
but being a journalist pays the bills.
평론가로 살면
돈도 제법 되죠
Just another second.
잠깐만 기다려요
내가 당신을 방해할 수
있을 거 같은데
I bet there's something I could do to distract you.
- I don't think so. - Mmm?
그렇지 않을걸요?
I might be wrong.
내가 틀린 거 같군요
I'm a little distracted.
살짝 방해되네요
Oh, whoa, hold on. What is it?
잠시만요
왜 그래요?
It's...
이건...
There's something on this tape.
주변의 마이크가 잡아낸
뭔가가 녹음됐어요
One of the ambient mics must have picked it up.
It's a voice.
목소리군요
Whose voice?
누구 목소리죠?
The man who blinded me.
내 눈을 멀게 한
남자예요
영자막 elderman
www.addic7ed.com
-==팎읔襟있蹈==-
굶俚캥쏭묩欺構슥직, 拮쐐痰黨庚둡촐
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
줅소큽景묏 뒤랗센뒤7섞
Season 2 Episode 7
Half a World Away
-=팎읔襟俚캥莉=-
럇陋：
叫뚤：
珂쇌菉:kami
한글번역 에렝아이
디시인사이드 기미갤
U.S FORWARD OPERATING BASE BAGHDAD, IRAQ
미군 전진 작전 기지
= 이라크, 바그다드 =
When I was there, I was with my brothers.
내가 거기 있을 때
난 형제들과 함께였죠
We found a way to make it like home
우린 그곳에서도
집처럼 지낼 수 있어요
even though it was the opposite of home.
비록 집과는 정반대의
장소이긴 했지만요
It was bleached out and scorching,
미칠듯이 더웠고
and the air was full of smoke, sand,
공기엔 연기와
모래가 가득했고
귀엔 폭발음이
아른거렸죠
and the ringing screams of bombs.
We had our own place in it.
우리만의 장소가
그 안에 있었죠
We had each other.
우리에겐 서로가
있었어요
And we had football.
또... 우리에겐
축구가 있었죠
* Hey baby *
* this is not a challenge *
♬ Discoverer ♬
R.E.M.
* just means that I love you *
* as much as I always said I did *
* I was wrong *
* I have been laughable wrong *
* sandpaper, paper mache, chalk *
* and hung out wet *
* that just the slightest bit of finesse *
* might have made a little less mess *
* but it was what it was *
* let's all get on with it *
* now *
* discoverer *
I don't know why you guys keep challenging us.
왜 자꾸 도전하는지
모르겠네
It only ever goes one way.
늘 일방적이잖아
Hey, uh, you mind taking a picture for us?
이봐, 사진 한 장
찍어주겠나?
.....
알겠습니다
Just try and frame out the burning buildings in the back.
저기 불타는 유전을
배경으로 잡아줘
It's kind of a downer. Let's go.
음울한 분위기로
자리들 잡아
Yeah. Good, good, good.
그래 좋아
THANKS....
고맙네
앤더슨 대위님
Captain Anderson, sir.
General Oubash wants you.
오바쉬 장군님이
찾으십니다
Put some clothes on, huh?
옷 좀 입으시죠
For his benefit, right? Not yours.
장군님을 위해서 말이지?
자네가 아니라?
Whatever.
어쨌거나요
You wanted to see me, sir?
찾으셨습니까?
최근에 자네 카드를
본 적 있나?
You looked at your Terror Deck recently?
Remember the Jack of Diamonds? Yes, sir.
다이아몬드 잭
기억하나?
그렇습니다
CIA paramilitaries have pinned down
CIA가 티그리트 외곽에서
놈의 은신처를 찾았어
his safe house outside Tikrit.
You've prepped for this. Now it's a go. Understand?
우리가 준비해온 일이
마침내 때가 온 거야
알겠나?
Yes, sir.
알겠습니다
Then get your men together and hit the road.
그럼 자네
대원들을 소집해서
길을 나서라고
Thank you, sir.
감사합니다
우리는 상반되는 두 가지
사실을 믿도록 훈련됐죠
We were trained to believe two opposites.
The first is that a man is nothing on his own.
첫째는 사람은 혼자서는
아무것도 못한다는 거예요
We were only and always a unit,
우리는 언제나
부대의 일원이었죠
one entity serving God and country.
신과 나라를 섬기는
하나의 독립체였어요
The second is that one brave individual's actions
둘째는 개인의
용감한 행동이
can change the shape of war.
전쟁의 양상을
바꿀 수 있다는 거예요
The army can't know whether you will be brave or cowardly in crisis.
군대는 누군가가
위기 상황에서
용맹할지 겁에 질릴지
알 수가 없어요
No one can.
아무도 모르죠
Although they preferred you to be brave.
용맹한 쪽을
원하더라도 말이에요
Annie Walker.
애니 워커입니다
- Hey, it's me. - Hey!
- 나예요
- 반가워요
How's Jazzapalooza? Great. How's Langleypalooza?
재즈팔루자는 어때요?
멋지죠
랭리팔루자는 어때요?
Oh, you would not believe
내 지난 36시간이
어땠을지 모를 거예요
what my last 36 hours have been like.
Three shifts on the Central American watch desk.
중앙 아메리카 감시만
3교대예요
If I have to read one more Nicaraguan email,
니카라과 쪽 이메일
하나만 더 읽어도
I think my eyes will bleed.
눈에서
피가 날 거 같아요
Can't wait to go home and get some sleep.
빨리 집에 가서
눕고 싶은 마음이에요
So you're completely game to doing me a big favor is what you're saying?
그럼 내가
어려운 부탁을 해도
들어줄 수
있다는 거겠죠?
I have the next two days off.
내일부터 이틀간
쉬는 날이에요
Lots of ice cream, bad movies, and sleep.
아이스크림 잔뜩이랑
쓰레기 같은 영화
거기에 잠
Lots and lots of sleep.
아주 긴긴 잠이요
That is my future. Okay, I misspoke.
그게 내 미래예요
좋아요
말을 잘못했네요
It's actually a very small favor,
실은 아주 작은
부탁이에요
and you'd be saving my butt.
내게 정말 큰 도움이
되는 일이에요
Sure. What is it?
알았어요
뭔데요?
Just a little something I forgot to wrap up before I left, and now it's bugging me.
떠나기 전에 챙기는 걸
깜빡한 게 있는데
신경이 쓰이네요
Could you look up the name Afran Felat Khani
아프란 펠랏 카하니란
이름을 검색해줄래요?
in the database and just confirm that he's deceased?
사망한 게 맞는지
확인 부탁해요
Khani, that's a Kurdish name?
카하니라면
쿠르드 이름인가요?
Yeah, he was an Iraqi terrorist during the war.
네, 전쟁 중에
이라크 테러리스트였죠
Just double-check his status.
카하니의 상태를
재확인하고 싶어서요
Would you? Shouldn't take you more than two minutes.
2분도 안 걸릴 거예요
Yeah, okay. I'll leave you a secure voicemail.
그래요
알았어요
보안 음성 우편으로
알려줄게요
Please. Oh, and, Annie,
부탁해요
아, 그리고 애니...
if you could just keep this between the two of us.
이건 비밀로 해줄래요?
It'd be really embarrassing if Joan found out.
조안이 알아낸다면
정말 난처할 거예요
- Sure, no problem. - You're a star.
- 알았어요
- 당신이 최고예요
The man is incapable of saying good-bye.
안녕이란 말을 하는 게
불가능한 남자라니까
카심?
Kasim.
Kasim. Auggie, welcome back.
- 카심?
- 오기, 돌아왔군
Hey, thank you.
You're here to see Sanem Kalfa?
그래, 고마워
사넴 칼파를
보러 온 거야?
You know me well, my friend. Take a seat. She's going to start soon.
잘 아는군, 친구
자리 잡아
곧 시작이야
You know what, before she does I have a question.
그전에 물어볼 게 있어
어제 녹음이 기대만큼
제대로 되지 않았어
My recording of the set yesterday didn't turn out exactly as I'd hoped.
I set up your mix perfectly, I promise.
자네 믹스 완벽하게
준비했었는데, 진짜야
그건 알아
이상한 부탁인데
I know you did. This is a strange request,
무대 북서쪽에
파라볼라 마이크
but did you set up any additional parabolic mics
on the northwest corner of the stage?
더 설치해둔 거 있어?
더 선명한 주변음을
잡아내고 싶어서 그래
I want to get some crisper ambient sound.
한번 볼게
Let me see.
보자...
맞아
I think I have something for you, but it was turned around in the breeze.
더 구할 수
있을 거 같아
하지만 바람 부는
방향에 있는데
Not sure you will get anything except wind.
바람 소리 밖에
안 들릴 거야
You know what, it might be worth listening to.
들을 가치가
있을지도 모르지
Would you mind burning those tracks for me?
그쪽 트랙도
구워줄 수 있어?
For you, Auggie, my pleasure.
Think I'm really onto something.
자네를 위해서라면
물론이지
뭔가 건질 수
있을 거 같아
Something wrong?
뭔가 잘못됐어?
No.
아뇨
Just doing some cleanup, and it says that a file's been removed.
정리를 좀 하고 있는데
파일이 제거됐다고 나오네요
Mmm, it's tough without Auggie around.
오기 없인
힘든 모양이네
Yeah.
네
It's just weird. I'll figure it out.
그냥 낯설어서요
알아서 할게요
Did you check the file tree? The file tree?
파일 트리는
확인했어?
파일 트리요?
Every file's connected with others in the same record.
모든 파일은 같은 기록의
파일들과 연결되어 있지
So if something's been removed, you can look at the ones around it.
뭔가 제거됐다면
주변 파일로 살펴볼 수 있어
Oh, great. Thanks.
그렇군요
감사합니다
Sure.
그래
Hey, just calling you back.
다시 전화하려고 했어요
Great. Listen to this.
잘 됐네요
들어봐요
Khani's been removed from the database.
카니는 데이터베이스에서
제거됐어요
But I followed the file tree, and he has a sister in Baltimore.
하지만 파일 트리를
따라가보니
볼티모어에
여동생이 살더군요
File tree.
파일 트리?
You're learning to speak nerd. I'm impressed.
컴퓨터광처럼 말하다니
인상 깊은데요?
I don't know how much more of this I can do while keeping it from Joan.
얼마나 오랫동안 조안에게
숨길 수 있을지 모르겠어요
It's your day off, so I'm guessing you don't have an active assignment.
쉬는 날이니까
임무는 없을 거 같은데요?
I'm going to Baltimore, aren't I?
볼티모어에
가야하는 거군요?
I wouldn't ask if it wasn't really important. Of course.
정말 중요하지 않았다면
부탁하지도 않았을 거예요
그렇겠죠
하지만 돌아오면
But when you get back, you're gonna tell me who this guy is, right?
누군지 꼭 말해줘요
알았죠?
This doesn't seem like some little thing you forgot to do.
당신이 깜빡할 사람은
아닌 거 같아요
Drive safe. Sorry, but I've gotta run.
운전 조심해요
미안한데
이만 끊어야겠어요
Did you get the additional tracks?
추가 트랙
얻었어요?
Yeah.
네
Anything good on them? Don't know yet.
괜찮은 거 있어요?
아직 몰라요
We have to go back. Gotta find some bells.
다시 가봐야겠어요
종소리를
찾아야 해요
Okay. I love treasure hunts.
알았어요
난 보물찾기
좋아해요
Listen, in a perfect world I'd be doing this by myself
할 수만 있다면
나 혼자 했을 거예요
for lots of reasons, but one of them
많은 이유가 있지만
그 중에 하난
is that you might have some questions that I can't answer,
내가 당신의 의문에
답해줄 수 없다는 거예요
and I don't think that's particularly fair to you.
그건 당신에게
불공평한 일일 거예요
I think I can decide what's fair to me.
불공평한지는
내가 결정할게요
I need you to be my eyes.
당신이 내 눈이
돼줬으면 좋겠어요
Let me get dressed.
옷부터 입고요
Okay, so we hear bells.
좋아요
종소리가 들리네요
고기 굽는
소리도 들리네요
I also hear sizzling meat.
카바츠 파는 노점도
근처에 있나요?
Are there any kabbatz carts nearby?
I mean, there's food stands everywhere.
음식 파는 노점은
어디나 있잖아요
이상하게 들리겠지만
This might sound strange, but there has to be rain around here somewhere,
어딘가에서
빗소리가 날 거예요
so think creatively.
창의력을
발휘해봐요
I happen to you know you're a girl with an imagination.
당신은 상상력이
풍부한 여자일 거 같아요
Okay.
알았어요
Okay, there's your rain.
찾았어요, 저기서
빗소리가 나네요
It's a rain stick.
레인 스틱이란 거예요
Never question this blind man about sound.
소리에 관한 한
맹인을 의심하지 말아요
I stand corrected. All right, what now?
잘못을 인정하죠
이제 어쩌죠?
GOOD STUFF
물건 좋아요
싸요, 싸
Very cheap, very cheap.
Move.
움직여요
Come on, let's go.
I thought you wanted to talk to him.
어서요
가죠
만나보려던 거
아니었어요?
That's the other voice on the tape.
테이프에 녹음된
또 다른 목소리예요
ROAD TO TIKRIT 67 KILOMETERS FROM BAGHDAD
티그리트로 가는 길
바그다드에서 67킬로미터
빌리, 그 음악은
도대체 뭐야?
Billy, what the hell is this music?
Jazz, baby.
재즈죠
데이브 홀랜드와
엘빈 존스의 협주예요
Played with Dave Holland and Elvin Jones.
Get into it.
- 빠져들어 보세요
- 별로 안 끌리는데
You're not convincing me, Billy.
You know the only reason I'll let you get away with that
대위님이 상관이니까
참는 거 아시죠?
is 'cause you outrank me, right?
You are a smart man, William. What's our E.T.A.?
자넨 영리한 친구야, 윌리엄
도착 예정 시각은?
Halfway there.
절반쯤 왔어요
I've waited two years for a mission like this, Captain.
이런 임무를 2년 동안
기다렸습니다. 대위님
제가 잡을 수 있도록
해주세요
You've got to let me take him out.
자네가 다이아몬드 잭을
죽이겠다고, 제이슨?
You're gonna kill the Jack of Diamonds, huh, Jason?
That's right. Who else?
맞습니다
또 누가 있겠어요?
I bet you a week's pay.
I'll take that action.
보너스가 나갈 텐데
그럼 저도
한번 해보죠
Stop.
멈춰요
정지
What the hell?
대체 뭐야?
Nasir, what do you see?
나시르
뭐가 보이지?
There's something in the road.
길에 뭔가 있습니다
Up ahead.
저 앞쪽입니다
That looks like a dead dog.
죽은 개
시체 같은데
All right, Nasir, come with me.
좋아
나시르, 날 따라와
Auggie.
오기?
Captain Anderson, please, don't take another step.
앤더슨 대위님
주의하세요
더는 앞으로
가지 마십시오
What did he say?
뭐라는데?
그냥 개 시체가
아니에요
It's not just a dead dog.
Looks like we're taking a different road to Tikrit.
티그리트까지
다른 길을 택해야겠군
가자
Let's go.
Where is he now? He's about half a block ahead.
지금은 어디 있죠?
반 블록쯤
앞에 있어요
I'm doing everything you said. I'm staying two cars behind.
당신 말대로 차량 두 대
간격을 유지하고 있어요
All right, good. Try not to tailgate.
좋아요
잘했어요
바짝 붙지 말고
Don't change lanes too often.
차선을 너무 자주
변경하지 말아요
And don't draw attention to yourself.
이목을 끌면 안 돼요
Okay. What kind of car is he driving?
알았어요
차량 종류는 뭐죠?
It's a black Mercedes C63 AMG.
검은색 벤츠
C63 AMG예요
직접 만든 가판대에서
북을 파는 남자치곤
Sweet ride for a guy selling drums
from a homemade stand.
훌륭한 차로군요
Must have some interesting side businesses.
뭔가 흥미로운
부업이 있는 거죠
BALTIMORE MARYLAND
볼티모어
= 메릴랜드 주 =
Excuse me. Are you Leyla Khani?
Do you have an appointment?
실례합니다, 당신이
레일라 카니인가요?
예약하셨나요?
Yeah. I'm so excited.
네, 정말 기대돼요
친구가 당신한테서
My friend said she got
the best manicure of her life here from you
평생 최고의 손톱 손질을
받았다고 했어요
and that it lasted forever.
That's so nice to hear.
기분 좋은
칭찬이네뇨
Please, choose your color and take a seat.
색을 고르시고
자리에 앉으세요
틀림없이
언니가 이걸 보면
I can almost guarantee you that when my sister sees this
똑같은 색 매니큐어를
칠하고 싶어할 거예요
she will want the exact same color. Well, send her here.
한번 오라고 하세요
Oh, she'll want to know exactly where I got it done.
어디서 받았는지
궁금해하겠죠
She's a little older than me, so she'd never admit it.
나보다 나이가 많아서
절대 인정하진 않지만
But secretly, she wants to be just like me.
언니는 남몰래
날 닮고 싶어해요
Well, that's the thing about family, isn't it?
그런 게
가족인 거 같죠?
Sometimes she wants to be like you.
가끔은 언니가
당신을 닮고 싶어하고
And sometimes she just wants to be close to you.
가끔은 당신과
함께 있고 싶어하죠
So I take it you have sisters?
A brother.
당신도 자매가 있는
모양이군요?
오빠요
And he wants to be just like you?
오빠도 당신을
닮고 싶어해요?
He's dead.
오빠는...
죽었어요
I'm sorry.
죄송해요
Hey, Auggie, it's me.
오기, 나예요
I made contact with Khani's sister.
카하니의 동생을
만나봤어요
She says he's dead, but I think she's hiding something.
오빠가 죽었다고 하는데
뭔가 숨기고
있는 거 같아요
Call me back.
연락해줘요
- Get in. - Agent Rossabi.
- 타요
- 로자비 요원?
So are you usually in the habit
of getting into strange cars because someone tells you to?
보통 남이
타라고 하면
수상한 차에도
그냥 올라타나 보죠?
I made you for FBI.
FBI 차량인 거 알아요
번호판이 확실한 증거죠
Your plates are a dead giveaway.
Really?
그래요?
How does someone who works at the Smithsonian
know what FBI plates look like?
스미소니언 직원이
어떻게 FBI 번호판을
알아보죠?
We had an exhibit on license plates through the ages.
저흰 오랜 기간 차량번호판을
전시하고 있어요
Wasn't very popular.
별로 인기 있는
전시품은 아니죠
제가 뭐
곤란해진 건가요?
Am I in trouble or something?
I don't know. Depends.
글쎄요
경우에 따라서요
- On what? - My mood.
- 무슨 경우요?
- 제 기분이요
레일라 카니를
방문한 일로
By visiting Leyla Khani you walked into an investigation
당신은 내가 3년 동안
공들인 수사에 끼어든 거예요
I've been working on for three years.
So what were you doing in there?
Getting my nails done.
거기서 뭐하던 거죠?
손톱 손질하러요
It's my day off.
쉬는 날이거든요
You drove all the way to Baltimore for that, really?
손톱 때문에
볼티모어까지 왔다고요?
Heard she's the best.
Oh, she is. She's one of our best assets.
최고라고 들었거든요
물론이죠, 우리 최고의
정보원 중 하나죠
And she's been feeding us information about her brother,
자기 오빠에 관한
정보를 넘겨주고 있었어요
Afran Felat Khani.
She told me he was dead.
아프란 펠랏 카하니예요
죽었다고 하던데요
I wish he was.
그랬다면
소원이 없겠죠
He's been operating cells in the Middle East since 2006,
2006년부터 중동에서
테러조직을 운영하고 있어요
targeting U.S. soldiers and interests.
미군과 미국의 이해관계를
목표로 삼고 있죠
A special forces unit even pursued him during the Iraq war,
이라크전 중에는 특수부대가
추적하기까지 했어요
and I am so close to nailing him.
내가 잡기
직전까지 왔다고요
그러니 당신이
레일라에게 겁을 줘서
So the last thing that I need
is for you to spook Leyla into cutting off our intel.
우리 정보가 끊기는 건
절대 사양이에요
Do you understand? That was never my intention.
- 알겠어요?
- 그럴 생각 없었어요
No, I know, I know.
네, 그렇겠죠
You were getting your nails done.
당신은... 손톱 손질
받으러 온 거니까
Did you say a special forces unit
특수부대가 전쟁 중에
카하니를 추적했다고 했어요?
was pursuing him during the war?
Yeah, why?
네, 왜요?
No reason.
그냥요
우회전해서 택심 광장으로
가고 있어요
........
OK....
좋아요
가까이 붙어요
.....
길이 좁아서
놓칠 수 있어요
I think he's going into a restaurant.
식당으로
들어가는 거 같아요
I'm gonna need you to wear this.
이걸 차줬으면 좋겠군요
Okay, not that I don't embrace this,
싫다는 건 아니지만
but we are in public in a Muslim country.
여긴 이슬람 사회의
공공장소예요
Right.
그렇군요
Also probably best if the blind man
도청장치
숨기는 일을
isn't in charge of hiding the bug.
맹인이 하는 것도
최선은 아니겠죠
- Okay, I'm ready. - Great.
- 준비됐어요
- 좋아요
I need you to go into the restaurant
and order a coffee, whatever drink you'd normally order.
식당에 들어가서
뭐든지 평소대로
커피를 주문해요
While it's being made,
만들어지는 동안
친구를 기다리는 것처럼
casually scan the restaurant like you're waiting
식당 안을 자연스럽게
둘러보도록 해요
for a friend who hasn't arrived yet.
Just be yourself and have fun.
그냥...
침착하고
상황을 즐겨봐요
알았어요
OKAY
커피 한 잔 주세요
I read somewhere that wars are not fought to kill people.
전쟁이란
사람을 죽이기 위해
싸우는 게 아니라는
이야기를 읽은 적 있어요
They're fought to affect political change,
정치적 변화를 위해
싸우는 거라고요
to move resources and borders.
자원과 국경을
움직이기 위해서요
Maybe that would be true if you were looking in
수천 마일이나
수백 년씩 떨어져서
from a thousand miles and a hundred years away.
전쟁을 지켜본다면
맞는 말이겠죠
To us, it was mostly about killing.
우리에겐 전쟁이란
대개 죽이는 거였어요
Maybe because we'd been sent there to kill.
죽이기 위해 보내졌기
때문이겠죠
。。。
정지
All right, here's the plan. Billy, you cover the front.
계획은 이거야
빌리, 네가
전방을 엄호해
I want a four man stack up to the breach.
구멍을 향해서
네 명이 나란히 서라고
STAY FOCUS.
다들 집중해
다이아몬드 잭의 은신처
= 티그리트 남부 =
.
JACK OF DIAMOND'S SAFE HOUSE SOUTHERN TIKRIT.
다이아몬드 잭의 은신처
= 티그리트 남부 =
조심해서 움직여
SMALL MOVES, GUYS.
....
내가 선두다
Chris and Jason, break off and lock up the rear.
크리스와 제이슨은
갈라져서 후방을 봉쇄해
Let's go.
가자
Billy?
빌리?
Sniper!
저격수다!
Chris! Damn.
크리스!
Chris.
크리스?
Chris, hey, look at me.
크리스, 이봐
내 쪽을 봐
Look at me, you stay strong. You're gonna be fine.
참고 견뎌봐
괜찮을 거야
Nasir, you're with Chris.
Jason, you're my cover. Let's go.
나시르, 크리스와
함께 있어
제이슨, 날 엄호해
움직이자
Okay, okay.
All clear.
상황종료
화물 적재실은
안전할 거라 확신합니까?
YOU'RE SURE THE CARGO HOLD WILL BE SECURE?
IT'S VERY IMPORTANT.
아주 중요한 문제입니다
OUR PEOPLE HAVE BEEN THROUGH IT TWICE TO CONFIRM.
우리 쪽 사람들이
자세히 확인했어
FLIGHT 1625, LEAVING SABIHA GOKEEN AT 4：00
4시에 사비하 고첸에서
떠나는 1625 비행편이야
AND SOMEONE WILL COLLECT ME IN LIMA?
리마에서 날 태워갈
사람은 있겠죠?
FROM THERE YOU'LL BE TRANSPORTED THROUGH PANAMA CITY TO WASHINGTON.
거기서부턴
파나마시티를 거쳐서
워싱턴으로
가게 될 거야
EVERYONE IS WAITING FOR YOU.
모두가 자넬
기다리는 곳이지
GOOD.
좋아요
THEN YOU HAVE VERTAINLY EARNED YOUR FEE.
그렇게 되면 당신에게
확실한 보상이 있을 거예요
THANK YOU.
고맙습니다
A THOUSAND THANK YOU.
대단히 고맙습니다
Hey, it's me.
나예요
Auggie, did you know Khani was being investigated
오기
FBI가 카하니를 수사 중인 거
알고 있었어요?
by the FBI?
Rossabi intercepted me in Baltimore
볼티모어에서
여동생을 만날 때
while I was visiting his sister.
로자비 요원이
날 붙잡더군요
So to answer your original question, he's not dead.
그러니 당신의 원래
질문에 대답하자면
카하니는
죽지 않았어요
But I think you already knew that.
- 이미 알고 있을 것 같네요
- 애니...
Annie, I have to make this fast.
난 서둘러야 해요
I have to be in Sanayi at 4:00.
싸나이에 4시까지
가야 해요
The concert can wait.
콘서트가
뭐 그리 급해요?
There was a special forces unit tracking him during the Iraq war.
이라크 전쟁 중에 특수부대가
카하니를 추적했다고 하던데
That was you, wasn't it?
당신이었죠?
Annie, I have something I have to tell you.
애니, 당신에게
말해야 할 게 있어요
해봐요, 왜 처음부터
말해주지 않았어요?
Please. Why could you have told me from the beginning?
Look, I want to thank you
이봐요
당신이 해준 모든 일에
고맙다고 말하고 싶어요
for all that you've done for me.
I am sorry that I didn't read you in,
사정을 숨겨서
미안해요
곤란한 일을
겪게 해서 미안하고요
and I'm sorry you went to all this trouble.
I truly am.
진심이에요
Auggie, please, tell me what's going on.
오기
부탁이에요
무슨 일인지 말해줘요
내가 도울게요
Let me help you.
다시 한번 고마워요
Thanks again. For everything.
이 모든 일에
안녕, 애니
Good-bye, Annie.
안녕...
Good-bye.
Yeah, Annie?
그래, 애니?
What is it? I hope it's not a bad time.
무슨 일이야?
안 좋은 시간이
아니라면 좋겠네요
Actually, I am having a terrible day.
실은 오늘 아주
일진이 사나운 날이야
My computer crashed again.
컴퓨터는
또 말썽이지
So unless you can fix a motherboard
그러니 네가 메인 보드를
고칠 수 있거나
or have some good news, it's a pretty bad time.
좋은 소식을
가져온 게 아니라면
안 좋은 시간이 맞아
I can't fix a computer
전 컴퓨터도
못 고치고
and I don't have good news,
좋은 소식도 없지만
but I do need your help.
도움이 필요해요
What is it, Annie?
무슨 일이야, 애니?
I've been working on something for Auggie.
He asked me to confirm
오기의 부탁을
들어주고 있었어요
어떤 이라크인
테러리스트의
that a certain Iraqi terrorist was dead. It was just a small favor,
사망을 확인해달라는
일이었죠
작은 부탁이었는데
알고 보니 작지 않았고
which turned out to be not so small when I walked into the FBI investigation
저는 그 남자에 대한
FBI 수사에 끼어들게 됐어요
of the man.
You did what?
뭘 어쨌다고?
I have a strong feeling that Auggie has located him in Istanbul
오기가 이스탄불에서
그자를 발견하곤
and is attempting to track and kill him on his own.
추적해서 직접 죽일 거란
예감이 들어요
What makes you think that?
왜 그렇게
생각하지?
He said he had to be in Sanayi, Mahali, by 4:00.
싸나이 마할리에 4시까지
가야한다고 했어요
First I thought it was for a concert,
처음엔 콘서트
이야기인 줄 알았는데
but the jazz festival never leaves Istanbul.
재즈 축제는 이스탄불을
벗어나지 않더군요
The only thing in Sanayi is a little airport.
싸나이에 있는 건
작은 공항뿐이에요
And the only flight leaving at 4:00
유일한 비행편이
4시에 떠나는데
is a cargo plane headed for Lima.
리마로 가는
화물수송기예요
Joan, he doesn't sound like himself.
조안, 말하는 게
오기답지 않았어요
I think something is really wrong. Who's the terrorist?
뭔가 크게
잘못된 거 같아요
테러리스트는 누구였지?
Afran Felat Khani.
아프란 펠릿 카하니요
Damn it, Auggie.
제길, 오기...
Do you know who that is?
누군지 아시나요?
Do you know why Auggie would be trying to track him?
왜 오기가 추적하려는지
아세요?
함정을 설치했다
대기하라!
"SETTING THE TRAP.STANDBY!"
Nasir?
나시르?
Hey, you gotta get out of there! There's a bomb!
빨리 벗어나!
폭탄이 있어!
크리스!
Chris! Jason!
제이슨!
Run!
도망쳐!
항공 교통 관제국의
오래된 친구를 통해서
I was able to get the plane's specifications
from an old friend in air traffic control.
비행기의 설계도를
얻을 수 있었어요
Tell me everything you see. How many aisles are inside?
보이는 모든 걸 말해줘요
내부에 복도가 몇이죠?
Uh, just one down the middle.
가운데로
하나뿐이에요
Cargo containers are at the front and back and along each wall.
화물 컨테이너는
각 벽을 따라
전후방에
하나씩 있어요
What's inside them?
내용물은요?
On this flight? Textiles.
이번 비행에서요?
섬유예요
There's rolls of silk, wool, and cotton.
비단이나 양모,
면 두루마리예요
카펫도 있고요
There's also some woven carpets.
Good, nothing to spill or break.
좋아요, 엎지르거나
부서질 건 없는 거군요
Do you see any measurements?
비행기의 제원에
관한 건 있나요?
The aisle's about 1 1/2 meters wide.
복도의 폭은
1.5미터고
The ceiling's about three meters high, so you won't hit your head.
천장은 3미터니까 머리를
부딪히진 않을 거예요
Good to know.
좋은 정보네요
Also the hold is the length of the plane minus the cockpit.
화물칸의 길이는
비행기에서 조종석을
뺀 길이예요
There's room to maneuver but nowhere to go.
그럼 달리 숨을 공간은
없다는 거군요
Just like I like it.
내가 원하는 대로예요
AGNET....
로자비 요원
만나줘서 고마워요
THANKS FOR Meeting me.
What can I do for you?
무슨 부탁을
하려고요?
Actually, it's something I can do for you.
실은 제가
도와드리는 거예요
Well, that's even better.
그럼 더 좋죠
In theory, of course,
물론 이건
하나의 가정인데요
if Afran Felat Khani were to roll out of a plane
아프란 펠렛 카하니가
비행기를 통해
워싱턴에 발을 내딛으면
onto a tarmac in D.C.,
does the FBI have enough evidence to prosecute him?
FBI에서 카하니를 기소할
충분한 증거가 있나요?
Five times over. What if the name of the airport
다섯 번은
더 할 수 있죠
비행편이나 도착시각이나
공항에 대한
and the time of the flight came to you as an anonymous tip?
익명의 제보가
들어온다면요?
The FBI is obligated to investigate
FBI는 테러 용의자에 대한
모든 익명의 제보를
조사해볼 의무가 있죠
all anonymous tips that relate to terror suspects.
Then I'd wait by your phone.
그럼 전화 기다리세요
사비하 고첸 공항
= 터키, 이스탄불 =
.
SABIHA GOKCEN AIRPORT ISTANBUL, TURKEY
사비하 고첸 공항
= 터키, 이스탄불 =
마일리지 얼마나 돼요?
How many miles do you have?
I work for an international airline.
난 국제선에서 일해요
I've got about 800, 000.
Then pick a place, anywhere in the world,
80만 마일쯤 될 거예요
약 130만 킬로미터
그럼 전 세계
아무 곳이나 골라요
and I will meet you there in a month.
한 달 안에
거기로 갈게요
Anywhere?
어디든지요?
Anywhere.
어디든지요
This really was the best layover I've ever had.
나한텐 이번이 정말
최고의 기착지였어요
Barbados?
바베이도스?
I'll buy the Planter's Punch.
칵테일은 내가 사죠
Hang on.
잠깐만요
발신자 표시 제한
Hello.
여보세요?
Hi, can I talk to Auggie, please?
안녕하세요, 오기와
얘기할 수 있을까요?
It's for you. I think it's your wife.
당신 전화예요
당신 아내인 거 같네요
She sounds rather upset.
조금 화난
목소리네요
Yes?
네?
You haven't been picking up your phone,
전화를 받지 않아서
so I had to resort to other measures.
다른 방법을
찾아야 했어요
오기...
Look, whatever you're about to do, don't.
무슨 일을
하려든지 간에
하지 마요
Annie, like I told you,
애니
얘기했다시피
it's complicated. It's not!
상황이 복잡해요
그렇지 않아요!
The FBI are ready to take Khani into custody.
FBI는 카하니를
체포할 준비가 됐어요
They have enough evidence to prosecute him
카하니를 기소할
증거도 충분하고
and shut down all of his networks.
카하니의 네트워크 모두
폐쇄할 수 있어요
That's dozens of cells all over the world
미국인과 미국의 이익을
공격하려는
전 세계에 퍼져 있는
십여 개의 조직들이죠
plotting attacks against Americans and American interests.
The Office of International Affairs at the Justice Department is on board.
법무부의 국제사무국도
참여하고 있어요
And we've arranged to reroute that flight to D.C.
비행기의 도착지도
워싱턴으로 변경했다고요
Please, Auggie, I know you're furious and hurt,
부탁이에요
오기
당신의 분노도 알고
당신이 받은
상처도 알아요
but this is what we do,
하지만 이게
우리 일이에요
what we work towards every day.
우리가 이루고자
늘 노력하는 거죠
Thousands of lives could be saved.
수천 명의 생명을
살릴 수 있어요
I'm sorry. It's too late.
미안해요
너무 늦었어요
내 아내가 아니에요
That wasn't my wife.
I don't have one.
난 아내가 없어요
Okay.
알았어요
Wait.
잠깐만요
How did you know you could trust me? I didn't know.
날 믿어도 될지
어떻게 알았죠?
몰랐어요
So thank you.
그래서 고마워요
짧은 지지대가 있고
다섯 걸음 밑으로 내려가요
There's a short plank and then five steps down.
After that, walk about 30 meters straight ahead.
그런 다음에
30미터 정도 직진이에요
Be careful.
조심해요
You?
넌?
DULLES AIRPORT WASHINGTON, D.C
덜레스 공항
= 워싱턴 DC =
♬ We did it when we were young ♬
The Gaslight Anthem
* Don't write me *
* no more letters *
* my mailbox is full *
상이 훈장이란
The Purple Heart is the only award the army gives out
추천이 아닌
자격으로 주는
for which you are not recommended
군의 유일한
훈장이에요
but entitled, from being injured.
군인의 부상에
따른 훈장이죠
난 자격이 있다고
전혀 생각하지 않았어요
I didn't think I was entitled at all.
So I didn't tell anyone about it.
그래서 아무에게도
말하지 않았죠
Until now.
여태까지는요
* We were strangers for many hours *
I can't imagine how hard that must have been for you.
얼마나 힘들었을지
짐작도 못 하겠어요
You did the right thing about Khani.
하지만 카하니에 대해서
당신은 옳은 일을 한 거예요
앞을 보지 못하면
잊게 되는 게 있죠
When you're blind, you forget things like color.
색이나
얼굴 같은 거요
Faces.
But I still remember that picture
하지만 난 여전히
그 사진을 기억해요
and every face and every color in it.
모든 얼굴과
모든 색을 기억하죠
I guess that's why I still carry it around with me.
그래서 아직 지니고
다니는 거 같아요
Which probably sounds strange
그건...
이상하게 들리겠죠
볼 수도 없으니까요
'cause I can't see it.
하지만 난
볼 수 있어요
But I can.
* There are not reasons * to believe
* I buried my faith *
* in another block *
Crisp and vivid every day.
언제나 선명하고
생생하게
It's the only thing I have from the war that seems pure.
전쟁이 내게 남긴
유일하게 순수한 거죠
마치...
Almost like it was from a time of peace instead.
평화의 시대에 찍은
사진 같아요
* We were lions, lovers in combat *
So now you know what happened to my unit.
이상이...
내 부대에
일어났던 일이에요
Thanks for telling me.
이야기해줘서
고마워요
Thanks for helping me.
도와줘서 고마워요
한 잔 더할래요?
You up for another round?
Yeah.
좋죠
- I have a question for you. - Yeah?
질문이 있어요
뭐죠?
How'd you get Franka's cell number?
프랭카의 전화번호는
어떻게 알았죠?
여자에겐 비밀이
있어야 해요
A girl's gotta have her secrets.
Oh, that's nice.
그거 멋지네요
피드백
whemie@gmail.com
* We were young *